<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Walter Virany</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Walter Virany</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Neural Network Gaussian Process</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nngp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nngp/</guid>
      <description>Despite their overwhelming success in modern machine learning, deep neural networks remain poorly understood from a theoretical perspective. Classical statistical wisdom dictates that overparameterized models (i.e., models with more degrees of freedom than data samples) should overfit noisy data and thus generalize poorly. Yet, even in cases in which deep neural networks fit noisy training data almost perfectly, they still exhibit good generalizability. This contradiction has highlighted a serious gap between the theory and practice of deep learning, motivating the need for a more complete theoretical framework for deep learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>I recently graduated from the University of Colorado with a B.S. in applied mathematics as well as minors in computer science and physics.&#xD;Broadly speaking, I am interested in machine learning, statistics, and optimization, typically with applications to biology.&#xD;News&#xD;3 Sep 2024&#xA;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Starting a research internship at Mila with Prof. Jian Tang 23 Jun 2024 &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Participating in RIPS at IPAM in Los Angeles for Summer 2024&#xA;9 May 2024 &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Graduate from CU Boulder!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
